Finding Aid for Hanna Family Papers, 1888-1945
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Hanna Family Papers, 1888-1945
Hanna Family.
0.5 linear ft.
8787 Aa 2
Gladwin, Michigan family. The collection consists of diaries, account books, and family miscellanea.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. Esther B. Munster (donor no. 7383 ) and came to the library in 1986.
The collection is open to research.
The first of the Hanna family in America was "Long John" Hanna, a timber worker who emigrated from Ireland to Michigan by way of Canada. His son Isaac began business in Cedar (present-day Gladwin) in 1878, as an undertaker and carpenter. His undertaking parlor remained in family hands for nearly a half century. Isaac Hanna died in 1908 and was succeeded in business by his son Will. Upon Will's death in 1926, his brother George sold the business to the embalmer, Bradley, who continued its operation under the name "Black and Bradley.''
The Hanna family collection consists of the diaries and account books generated by various members of the Hanna family of Gladwin, Michigan. Isaac Hanna's diaries comment on his business dealings and activities as a town official. They were transcribed by Esther Munster, daughter of Isaac's son Will, who also provided the biographical information incorporated in this introduction.
Subjects:
Business records.; Gladwin (Mich.); Hanna, George.; Hanna, Isaac, 1848-1908.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1881-1890.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1891-1900.; Michigan--Social life and customs--19th century.; Undertakers and undertaking--Michigan--Gladwin.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Dwellings--Michigan--Gladwin.; Gladwin (Mich.)--Dwellings.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
- Isaac Hanna Diaries
  (includes transcripts)
  - 1888 (Box 1)
  - 1890 (Box 1)
  - 1891 (Box 1)
- Hanna family
  - Biographical information (Box 1)
  - Account books of Hanna family funeral home and furniture store
    - 1902-1909 (Box 1)
    - 1934 1938 (Box 1)
    - 1945 (Box 1)
      (also includes schoolwork, 1919-1924, and diary, 1929-1936, kept by George Hanna)
    - 1908-1909 (Box 1)
    - 1915 (Box 1)
    - 1916 (Box 1)
    - 1928 (Box 1)
    - 1929 (Box 1)
    - 1931 (Box 1)
    - 1934-1937 (Box 1)
    - 1942 (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
    - Isaac Hanna's home in Gladwin, Michigan, 1942 (Box 1)